The code we have seen so far to work with files
is efficient but can sometimes seem cumbersome.
We can consolidate the amount of code we have
to write using the with statement, which opens
a file, performs an action on a file, and then
closes that file without having to tell Python to
close the file. Having a file close ensures that
the memory space the file uses will be recovered,
thus helping a device run more efficiently and
reducing the chance of data corruption. In this
318-with code file, we have the same first four
lines of code as we did for the video on writing
to a file. Starting on line 6, I am going to
rewrite this code, using the with keyword, and you
will see the difference in the code efficiency. I
will type with, copy the open statement from line
1 to here, add the words as message, and then a
colon. I will make sure the next line is indented
as with is a block of code, and then I will copy
the two write statements to lines 7 and 8 and
ensure both are indented. Then, I will comment
out the code on lines 1 through 4. On line 9,
I will add a print statement to tell us the file
has been created. Then I will run this code,
and the file has been created. The file management
section is complete, so it is time for a code
analysis exercise. This 318-analysis file has the
same code we just worked on, with one addition:
a print statement to read the code on line 10.
Use the Review 3.1 exercise in the workbook to
answer questions on this code. In the next video,
we will discuss the answers to those questions.